Hello everyone. In this video, I'll be
showing you the most OP Lazelle build
for patch 8 of Balderscade 3. There were
some big changes to the game, additions
to the spell list, and things like
booming blade, which redefine the meta,
and I'll be breaking down the best
choices here for Lazelle. So, we're
going to keep her as a fighter here as
obviously that is what she's suited to
be best. And we're going to take great
weapon fighting. So, if you roll a one
or two for a damage down and a
two-handed melee attack, the damage is
rerolled once. Early game defense can be
nice for that increase to armor.
Honestly, the plus one armor class is
always a good choice. You could go with
that alternatively. And for our ability
scores here, it really depends. If we
want to focus more on like dexterity and
be a more kind of stealth base, we could
go with the 16 dexterity, 16 strength,
or we can go 16 constitution, 16 uh
strength like this. We do need a little
bit of intelligence. However, there is
an item that can help with that if we
want to use it with the circle of
intelligence. But we can alternatively
also boost our armor class a bit if we
want to wear medium armor and go with
like the armor of agility and be a bit
more of a uh like a kind of all-in-one
kind of character. So we could go with
this or the 16 constitution there.
Alternatively, we can use a constitution
amulet and dump our constitution and put
those points into our intelligence
there. So that is another good option to
go with and we can go something like
that to have no negative saves. Level
two gives us the ever powerful action
surge. So we get an extra action. You
know how good that is. And in honor
mode, it actually lets you do extra
attacks, whereas haste doesn't. So, into
level three here, we get to choose our
subclass, and we're going to go with the
Eldrich Knight. Now, where this really
shines is booming blade. This is a very
powerful ability, so we're going to go
with that. I also like to have mage hand
or minor illusion for other cantrips.
Mage hand's nice because we can use it
to throw healing potions or health or
water bottles, you name it. And for the
spells, I think that shield is going to
be a very useful one to have because
this can increase your armor class by
five, preventing you from getting hit.
Magic missile is a nice one and so is
thunderwave. Just push back or a
guaranteed damage on far away targets
can be good. Sometimes magic missile is
the only spell that can actually hit a
target. And for our extended spell list,
fine familiar can be a good one because
you can give yourself a raven and that's
just a nice way to help out with
blinding targets. Grease is also a good
one to have and long strider for an
increased movement speed. So, I'm going
to go with long shroud there as that
fits very well on this class. But if you
someone else with long shredder, you can
obviously give that to them. At level
four, we get ourselves another spell
choice. And I mean, Thunderwave is a
good choice to go with. And for the
feat, I would recommend going with an
increase to either our strength or our
dexterity. Now, if you really want to m
minax this, strength potions are the way
to go. So, we could even just dump
strength and and go that way. Uh, for
the best armor class, I'm going to go
dexterity. Normally, if you don't want
to use strength potions, put your
strength up. I'm just going to give you
two different options to go more tanky
or go more into the uh offensive focus.
And again, not everyone wants to use
strength potions. Extra attack at level
five. You know how powerful that is. Um
so that's great. Into level six, we get
ourselves another feat which we can use
to increase a stat. However, I think
it's actually best to go with the great
weapon master. Now, this gives us a
minus five to attack rolls, but plus 10
damage, which is huge. And if we can
actually uh offset this minus two attack
rolls and I'll show you how to do that.
There's a nice little multiclass we can
do for a single level. We also get a
free bonus action attack, but we also
get bonus action attacks as you'll see
here as the Eldrich Knight. So yeah,
we'll go with the great weapon master
better damage into level seven. We get
war magic after you cast a cantrip
moving blade counts. You can make a
weapon attack using a bonus action. So
you're going to see this becomes really
crazy. And for our spells here, darkness
can be nice if you have like the
Eversight ring or the um the Steel
Watcher helmet. So, this can actually be
extremely useful uh for just
survivability sake. Not a lot of these
spells are ones you're going to want to
use often because it's probably best for
us to get in close and do a melee attack
or use our Eldrich Bond to throw a
weapon like Nyola. However, I'm going to
use the get the Yankee sword here as I
find that that works very well. From the
expendit spell list, you can see we got
a lot of choices. I think missy step is
a solid choice. Hold person's good, but
we're not built fully around
intelligence, so they're not going to
have a great chance of landing that.
Mirror image is another good choice. And
another really good choice, shadow
blade. I've done a bunch of builds using
shadow blade, so I'm not going to use it
for this one just cuz I do get
complaints whenever I use it. So, we'll
go with misty step cuz extra mobility
extremely useful. She does already have
a misti step built in. Uh, but more
misty step is never a bad thing. Um, we
do have a bonus action use, so it's not
always ideal, but sometimes you need a
misty step to hit a target.
Alternatively, mirror image for that
plus 9 armor class makes us extremely
tanky as well. So, if you don't want to
use that misty step, mirror image is
good, too. And now we can boost up our
dexterity or strength to its maximum.
Again, I'm going to use strength potions
to show the full power of this build.
Little nine indomitable. If you fail a
saving throw, rroll that. Go again.
Level 10, we get the Eldrich Strike.
When we hit a creature with a weapon
attack, it has disadvantage on saving
throw against a spell you cast before
the end of your next turn. This is nice
for like hold person and we can choose
another caner. I think that firebolt's
good for exploding things, but also
mirror image is also kind of nice
because you can use that to uh confuse
enemies before you get into combat. And
for our next level spell, arcane lock is
kind of fun. U we're not going to be
using a lot of these. Even gust of wind
can be a good choice. Shatter, you're
going to not be using much outside of
booming blade, missy stab, mirror image.
Level 11 extra attack. So we can do
three attacks and then booming blade for
a fourth attack. It's pretty crazy. And
we get to take another spell here. Um, I
guess chromatic orb can be a good
choice. If you got a shadow magic
sorcerer, you can hit them with it. You
can hit their target with that. Now, we
could go for another feat and take like
savage attacker. However, I think it's
best to actually go ahead add in the
paladin oath of the crown cuz the
righteous clarity will add our
proficiency bonus to our attack rolls.
It gives us a nice uh plus4 to our
attack rolls. So, that offsets our great
weapon master quite a bit and uh just
makes us much easier to hit. Although,
you do have an oath that you have to be
mindful of. he could break it. But uh
then you also get advantage on saving
throws against or attack rolls against
fiend celestials and undead and you get
the lay hands charges. So what this will
look like. So I went with the helmet
baldd here which can give us a plus one
armor class and saving throws heals us
and we can't be critically hit. Now I
did mention you can go with the cirlet
of intelligence cuz this can give you um
your intelligence up to 17. So that' be
a plus three to intelligence if you want
to spell cast. We're not much of a
spellcaster. Our spells like magic
missile are guaranteed to hit anyways.
So, it's not something We're mostly
going to be using booming blade and our
uh weapon bond here. So, that's nice. Um
the weapon bond being really nice cuz it
returns the weapon to our hand. We
aren't going to throw our sword though.
That's doesn't really work out too well.
Uh cloak protection, better armor class.
Same armor of agility. However, this
adds our full dexterity. That's why in
this version I built around dexterity.
And then we can just go with a strength
potion. So, we can go with boom, take
one of these, pop it. Now, we have 27
strength. So, that's really powerful. We
could have also put some of those points
from strength into our intelligence. Um,
but this gives us the highest armor
class because if we were to use the
other best armor, the armor of
persistence, 23 armor class, held armor,
24, but with that armor of agility, 25.
And this is without a shield, mind you.
So, that's pretty good. The gauntlets of
surgeon accuracy work well, too. So,
that gives a 1d4 bonus to attack rolls
for the rest of your turn after using
action surge. Uh, so that can be a good
choice to go with. If you want, you
could even go with something like the
held gloves late game. Obviously, it's
going to add additional fire damage to
your attacks. Uh, Legacy of the Masters
will give us a plus two attack and
damage rolls. Guarantee that we hit,
which is kind of nice. We get a plus six
to our attack rolls, meaning that we're
much more likely to land our attacks.
Um, early game, you could go with the
gloves of dexterity as an option. Um, so
you could go alternatively with that or
the gloves of missile snaring to prevent
your team from getting hit ability with
something like that. Alternatively, it's
disintegrating night walkers because
that'll give us another missy step. Even
though we have our getankee step, we got
we can get two of them here. Or we could
go with the evasive shoes that puts our
armor class up to 26. And then ring of
protection, killer sweetheart, and
amulet of greater health paired with the
hell rider long bow for the plus three
initiative. And we're going to use the
silver sword of the astral plane getting
us additional 1d6 piercing our psychic
cuz we are a githani. And we also get
advantage on intelligence, wisdom, and
charisma saving throws, which is huge.
So, we're much less likely to get hit
with my commands and hold person and
resistance to psychic damage and it
cannot be charmed. So, that's pretty
good damage. Now, you can see here
booming blade can do upwards of a 57
damage on an attack and we can attack
four times per turn. So, it's actually
pretty powerful. So, with getting into
combat here, we got some pretty
effective abilities like booming blade.
Um, we can also go ahead with applying a
righteous clarity to ourel if we don't
have a great hit chance. We currently
have a 95% hit chance, so we don't
really need that. But, uh, we can start
off with a booming blade here. So,
that's an attack. And then we can follow
it up with taking out that target. We
can follow it up with an attack. Um, and
then we can also follow that one up with
an attack. And if that doesn't work, we
can always follow it up with another
attack. Another fun thing you can do is
the Gith Yankee Mageant. Um, what it can
do is it can throw health potions and
uh, those are pretty nice. So, we can go
boop and heal ourselves. So yeah, if you
need a little extra health, our little
Gith Yankee hand. We have two different
mage hands and they're nice just for
that a little healing effect. So we can
also take our armor class up even higher
by using mirror image here. So that is
another nice thing is we got defense
like crazy here. So that puts our armor
class up to 37 and that's without using
a shield. Um so yeah, our next way to go
about doing things, booming blade again
and uh she can hit really hard there. 38
and seven. Pretty crazy. And then we'd
follow it up. The nice thing about this
is we get so many extra attacks. It's
pretty crazy. So boom, boom, boom. And
then we got our extra extra attack. So
that's four attacks per action. And then
if you want to go crazy with an action
surge, that's another three more
attacks. So yeah, it's actually pretty
powerful how strong that Lazelle can get
with this combination. So yeah, now the
thing with Lazelle is she's a front
liner, so we want to get her in and
attacking as much as possible. It's
always a nice thing to start off with
the booming blade there because you can
see the damage potential on it is
insane. So, that was a pretty good hit
there and then finish them off and move
on to the next targets. We used two
attacks so far. Here's the third attack
and we rolled a critical hit on it.
Perfect. And here's the fourth attack.
And um yeah, we can roll a critical hit
on it. And here's the fifth attack going
up on our sixth attack. Critical hit.
And then we can go for our seventh
attack here, which should be our final
one. And then we can go with our Eldrich
or our action surge for another attack.
So yeah, pretty crazy. And then we can
follow it up by going after a couple
more targets and finishing them off. So
we we got just enough movement speed to
be able to attack. Perfect. And there's
one more critical hit and hopefully to
finish them off. Boom. Nice. So yeah, if
we had another bonus action, we would
have another attack, but that was more
than enough. And if we had elixir of
blood lust too, we would have had
another one. And I should have mentioned
taking darkness means that we want to
have like the ever ever sight ring or go
with the um seal watch or helmet here,
which prevents you from being blinded.
Alternatively, you could go with the
sharp spear of the evening, too. But uh
darkness is nice because it gives you
advantage on your attacks whenever
targets can't see within it. Um, and
that's a nice boost to our overall
survivability. But normally we can just
go ahead with our good oldfashioned boom
blade combo with the um with our attacks
there. So we got another attack. Yeah,
the thing with fighters you as you know
is all the extra attacks. Haste will not
give them those extra attacks in honor
modes. That's something to keep in mind.
It just gives them that extra one
attack. We unfortunately lost our haste
there. Um, and we don't have a bonus
action to be able to attack. So that's
unfortunate. Anytime it's our turn,
we're always going to be using our
booming blade here because yeah, the
damage potential on is insane. We could
also let them go and if they move,
they'll end up taking damage. So, that
can be kind of nice, too. Uh, we al we
got a critical miss there. That happens.
And we can use the shield to keep
ourselves safe. Um, and you just follow
up with another attack. We took out our
target. We got a great weapon master
extra attack. We don't get to use that
too too often just because of the uh
booming blade here, which is only usable
once per action. But we also have the
soul breaker from the sword. So, that's
another really powerful attack which can
stun targets. And when they're stunned,
you can just leave them alone and they
just skip their turn. So, and you know
what time it is? It's booming blade
time. That should finish them off.
Perfect. And then we can hunt down our
last prey here to get them completely
finished off. So, yeah, that is a pretty
powerful Eldrich Knight build. Really
big buffs. Again, you can take shadow
blade if you wanted to cuz shadow blade
is extremely effective. Um, the booming
blade obviously being a big highlight of
this. We could also go with our weapon
bond here too if we want to go full in
on throwing and you could even use
what's nice is the char spear of the
evening can pair well with the darkness.
So you can use uh that if you're on an
evil playthrough. So sharp spear of the
evening there um cannot be blinded and
it's a throwin weapon which will return
to your hand with a weapon bond. So
that's another cool choice if you wanted
to. Let me know your thoughts in the
comments below. Hit the subscribe button
if you haven't already and I'll see you
all in the next video.